Guide to the Edith McChesney Ker papers, 1948-2003
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
Edith McChesney Ker papers
1948-2003
C0077
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
15.0 linear feet, 48 boxes
This collection contains approximately 10,000 slides, scrapbooks, publications, and archival materials relating to Edith Ker's nature expeditions and travels around the world.
Ker, Edith McChesney, 1924-2003
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Jean Moretti in October 2005.
Biographical Information
An avid photographer of wildlife and nature, Edith "Edie" Ker dedicated her life to traveling around the world taking photographs and writing journal entries about her experiences. During the course of her career, Ker participated in more than 70 professional photographic camping safaris in Africa, including expeditions with primatologist Jane Goodall. She also served as president of the Society of Woman Geographers from 1997 to 1999. Born in 1924, she died in 2003.
Scope and Content
This collection contains approximately 10,000 slides, as well as photographs, scrapbooks, publications, and audio visual materials relating to Edith Ker's nature expeditions. Aside from visiting safaris in Africa, she traveled all over the world to countries like Canada, Russia, Australia, Turkey, Namibia, Argentina, and around the United States. She kept scrapbooks of each trip to showcase postcards, articles, research notes, itineraries, pictures, and brochures from her travels. Her photographs capture a variety of different animals from around the world as well as buildings, landscapes, and people.
Arrangement
This collection was arranged by the following formats: paper documents, slides, and scrapbooks, with the exception of audio visual materials, which are housed in Boxes 1 and 34.
Alternative Form Available
Digitized versions of items in Boxes 11-17 and 46-48 can be found here:.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center also holds the.
Index Terms
Persons:
Ker, Edith McChesney, 1924-2003
Geographical Names:
Africa--Slides.; Canada--Photographs.; Europe--Geography--Slides.; South America.; Middle East.
Subjects:
Nature.
Document Types:
Postcards.; Scrapbooks.; Slides.; Video recordings.
Contents List
- Original Copies of Descriptions of the Ker Collection Films #1-#13, 1948; 1960-1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Original Folder that Contained Descriptions of the Ker Collection Films #1-#13, circa 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Descriptions of the Ker Collection Films #1-#7, #12-#13, 1948; 1960-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "Ker Collection Film #1 0-2750; Film #2 2750-5400", 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "Ker Collection Film #4 0-2740; Film #5 2740-4435", 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "Ker Collection Film #6 0-1800; Film #7 1800-3480", 1948; 1965 (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "Ker Collection Film #8 0-2850; Film #9 2850-4875", circa 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "Ker Collection Film #10 0-2830; Film #11 2830-4754", 1966-1975 (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "Ker Collection Film #12 0-3035; Film #13 3035-4095", 1970s (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "BABE", undated (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "Elephants of Africa-Cynthia Moss", November 16, 1997 (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "Echo of the Elephants-1994?; Echo of the Elephants: The Next Generation", January 19, 1997 (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
- "Skeleton Coast Safari", May 1996 (Box 1, Folder Videotape (VHS))
  4+ hours
- Songs, Stories, Poems, and Jokes, 1958; 1970-2003 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Photograph of Flowers for Edith Ker, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence from Edie Ker to Mr. and Mrs. Reginald B. Taylor Re: African Safaris, June 1964-March 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Ker's Air Mileage (From Her Trips), circa 1950s-2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "Around the Campfire," by Edie Ker Alexandria, VA 1988 (Original Copy) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "Around the Campfire," by Edie Ker Alexandria, VA 1988 (A Gift to Dean and John from Edie) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Photograph of Don Ker, Hugo Van Lawick, Edie Ker, and Jane Goodall, circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Postcards of African Wildlife (Some Written on by Edie Ker), circa 1960s (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence to/from Edie Ker and American Museum of Natural History About the Acquisition of Don Ker's Reels of Safari Films, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Photograph of Edith Ker in her Later Years, circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- William and Mar Alumni Gazette, March 1964 "Safaris Are My Life" by Edie McChesney Ker, '45 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Commemorative Issue CIVILIZATION: The Library of Congress Celebrates the 100th Anniversary of the Thomas Jefferson Building 1897-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Scrapbook of Comics Regarding Animals, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Alaska Maps, Brochures, Reading List; Negatives New Zealand and Africa, 1980-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Britain Cruise (Itinerary, Brochures, Maps, Reading List), 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Canadian Rockies and Pacific NW (Itinerary, Brochures, Maps), 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Eastern Europe (Budapest, Kakopane, Krakow, Prague: Itinerary, Brochures, Maps), 1977-1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Eastern Shore (U.S.) (Maps and Brochures), 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Egypt (Itinerary, Brief History on Egypt, Map), circa 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Everglades (Itinerary, Brochures, Maps), 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- France (3 Maps), circa 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Nova Scotia (Brochures, Maps), circa 1990-1995 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Passage Through History (Exploring Coastal Iberia, France, Britain, and the Irish Isles; Itinerary, Brochures, Maps), circa 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Saskatchewan Manitoba [Brochures (VENT, VAN O'S), "Polar Bear Do Not Litter" trashbag], circa 1975-1989 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Argentina and Chile (Itinerary, Maps, Brochures), 1976; circa 1989-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Beyond the North Cape, Log of Cruise P210 Aboard the M.S. Polaris, July 8 to July 21, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- East African Wildlife Society Calendar. Photo of Lion Group by Edie Ker., March 1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- East African Wildlife Society Calendar. Photo of Zebra at Waterhole by Edie Ker., April 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- East African Wildlife Society Calendar. Photo of Ahmed, Elephant by Edie Ker., October 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- East African Wildlife Society Calendar. Photo of Serengeti Rainbow by Edie Ker., January 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Articles on Tourism and Wildlife in West Virginia and Maryland (Maps), circa 1983-2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Savannah and Charleston (Maps and Brochures), circa 1990s (Box 4, Folder 8)
- South Pacific; Australia, Fiji, New Zealand (Brochures, Maps), circa 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Southwest; Arizona, Utah, New Mexico, Colorado (Itinerary, Brochures, Maps, Reading List), circa 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- The Log of Circumnavigating the British Isles Aboard the Polaris, by Special Expeditions, Inc., June 7 to June 21, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Turkey (Itinerary, Brochures, Maps), circa 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Around the World #1 (Journal), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Around the World #2 (Journal), 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- England #1 and England #2 (Journals), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Europe (Journal), 1954 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Russia (Journal), August 2003 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Scotland (Journal), September 1999 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Australia, New Zealand, Fiji #2 (Journal), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Canadian Rockies (Journal), September 2001 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Eastern Europe (Journal), 1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Egypt (Journal), March 1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- New Zealand (Journal), 1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Pacific Northwest (Journal), September 2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- U.S. and Canada (Journal), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- U.S. West (Journal), 1950 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Baja (Journal), 1981; 1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Malta-Norway-U.S. (Journal), 1970 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Namibia-Zimbabwe, August 1995 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Savannah-Charleston (Journal), April 1997 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- St.Petersburg, Sweden, July 2001 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Argentina, Chile, Easter Island (Journal), 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Everglades and Beyond; Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube Cruise (Journals), September-October 1997; April 1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Galapagos-U.S. (Journal), 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Gaspe; Canyons of Time; Alaska II; Alaska III (Journals), 1989; 1990; 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Italy; Finland, Norway (Journals), November 1999; July 2000 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- SWA-Botswana, Namibia-Botswana (Journal), 1984 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Galapagos #2 (Journal), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Map of Guernsey, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Nova Scotia; Turkey; Spitzbergen (Journal), 1994; May 1994; July 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Patagonia (Journal), 1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- South Pacific (Journal), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Switzerland; Scandinavia; Holland-Belgium (Journal), 1983; 1987; 1992 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- U.K. Cruise; Passage Through History (Journal), 1991; 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Western Cruise; France; Polar Bears; Alaska I (Journal), 1983; 1985; 1985; 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Descriptions of Trips, September 1983-July 1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Descriptions of Trips, October 1985-October 1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Descriptions of Trips, August 1990-July 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Descriptions of Trips, April 1993-March 1996 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Descriptions of Trips, October 1996-August 2003 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Patagonia November 1991 #1 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  20 Slides; Color
- Patagonia November 1991 #1 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Patagonia November 1991 #1 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Patagonia November 1991 #1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Patagonia November 1991 #1 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Patagonia November 1991 #1 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Patagonia November 1991 #1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Patagonia November 1991 #2 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Patagonia November 1991 #2 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Patagonia November 1991 #2 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Patagonia November 1991 #2 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Patagonia November 1991 #2 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Patagonia November 1991 #2 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Patagonia November 1991 #2 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Notes on Patagonia and Argentina, circa 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #1, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #1, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #1, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #1, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #1, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #1, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #1, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #2, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #2, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #2, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #2, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #2, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #2, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Argentina-Chile-Easter Island #2, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Notes on Slides-Easter Island, November 1993 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Galapagos 1972 #1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Galapagos 1972 #1 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Galapagos 1972 #1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Galapagos 1972 #1 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Galapagos 1972 #1 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Galapagos 1972 #1 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Galapagos 1972 #1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Galapagos 1972 #2 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Galapagos 1972 #2 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Galapagos 1972 #2 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Galapagos 1972 #2 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Galapagos 1972 #2 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Galapagos 1972 #2 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Galapagos 1972 #2 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Guatemala, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  20 Slides; Sepia
- Guatemala, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Guatemala, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Gaspe 1989 #1 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Gaspe 1989 #1 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Gaspe 1989 #1 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Gaspe 1989 #1 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Gaspe 1989 #1 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Gaspe 1989 #1 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Gaspe 1989 #1 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  16 Slides; Color
- Gaspe 1989 #2 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Gaspe 1989 #2 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Gaspe 1989 #2 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Gaspe 1989 #2 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Gaspe 1989 #2 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Gaspe 1989 #2 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Gaspe 1989 #2 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  3 Slides; Color
- Nova Scotia/ Carousel 1, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Nova Scotia/ Carousel 1, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Nova Scotia/ Carousel 1, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Nova Scotia/ Carousel 1, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Nova Scotia/ Carousel 1, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Nova Scotia/ Carousel 1, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Nova Scotia/ Carousel 1, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  18 Slides; Color
- Nova Scotia 1994 #2 (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Nova Scotia 1994 #2 (Box 13, Folder 23)
- Nova Scotia 1994 #2 (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Nova Scotia 1994 #2 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  7 Slides; Color
- Norway 2000 #2 (Box 13, Folder 26)
- Norway 2000 #2 (Box 13, Folder 27)
- Norway 2000 #2 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  8 Slides; Color
- Savannah Charleston NVA, April 1997 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Savannah Charleston NVA, April 1997 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Savannah Charleston NVA, April 1997 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Savannah Charleston NVA, April 1997 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Savannah Charleston NVA, April 1997 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Savannah Charleston NVA, April 1997 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Savannah Charleston NVA, April 1997 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  15 Slides; Color
- Everglades, April 1998 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Everglades, April 1998 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Everglades, April 1998 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Everglades, April 1998 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Everglades, April 1998 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Everglades, April 1998 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Everglades, April 1998 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Maine, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Maine, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Maine, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Maine, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- Maine, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Maine, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- Maine, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  19 Slides; Color
- Canadian Rockies, September 23-30, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Canadian Rockies, September 23-30, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 23)
- Canadian Rockies, September 23-30, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 24)
- Canadian Rockies, September 23-30, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Canadian Rockies, September 23-30, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 26)
- Canadian Rockies, September 23-30, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 27)
- Canadian Rockies, September 23-30, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 28)
- Polar Bears, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 29)
- Polar Bears, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 30)
- Polar Bears, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 31)
- Polar Bears, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 32)
- Polar Bears, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 33)
- Polar Bears, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 34)
- Polar Bears, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  17 Slides; Color
- Alaska 8/86 #1, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Alaska 8/86 #1, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Alaska 8/86 #1, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Alaska 8/86 #1, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Alaska 8/86 #1, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Alaska 8/86 #1, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Alaska 8/86 #1, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Alaska 8/86 #2, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Alaska 8/86 #2, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Alaska 8/86 #2, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Alaska 8/86 #2, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Alaska 8/86 #2, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Alaska 8/86 #2, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Alaska 8/86 #2, August 1986 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #1, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #1, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #1, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #1, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #1, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #1, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #1, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #2, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #2, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 23)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #2, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Alaska Aug. 1990 #2, August 1990 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  10 Slides; Color
- Alaska III July 1992 #1 (Box 15, Folder 26)
- Alaska III July 1992 #1 (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Alaska III July 1992 #1 (Box 15, Folder 28)
- Alaska III July 1992 #1 (Box 15, Folder 29)
- Alaska III July 1992 #1 (Box 15, Folder 30)
- Alaska III July 1992 #1 (Box 15, Folder 31)
- Alaska III July 1992 #1 (Box 15, Folder 32)
- Alaska III July 1992 #2 (Box 15, Folder 33)
- Alaska III July 1992 #2 (Box 15, Folder 34)
- Alaska III July 1992 #2 (Box 15, Folder 35)
- Alaska III July 1992 #2 (Box 15, Folder 36)
- Alaska III July 1992 #2 (Box 15, Folder 37)
- Alaska III July 1992 #2 (Box 15, Folder 38)
- Alaska III July 1992 #2 (Box 15, Folder 39)
- Baja 1985 #1 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Baja 1985 #1 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Baja 1985 #1 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Baja 1985 #1 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Baja 1985 #1 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Baja 1985 #1 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Baja 1985 #1 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  14 Slides; Color
- Baja 1985 #2 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Baja 1985 #2 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Baja 1985 #2 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Baja 1985 #2 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Baja 1985 #1 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Baja 1985 #2 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Baja 1985 #2 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Baja Notes, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #1, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #1, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #1, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #1, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #1, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #1, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #1, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #2, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #2, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 24)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #2, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 25)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #2, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 26)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #2, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 27)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #2, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 28)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #2, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 29)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #3, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 30)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #3, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 31)
- Canyons of Time Oct. 1990 #3, October 1990 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  12 Slides; Color
- Turkey May 1994 #1 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Turkey May 1994 #1 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Turkey May 1994 #1 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Turkey May 1994 #1 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Turkey May 1994 #1 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Turkey May 1994 #1 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Turkey May 1994 #1 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Turkey May 1994 #2 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Turkey May 1994 #2 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Turkey May 1994 #2 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Turkey May 1994 #2 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Turkey May 1994 #2 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Turkey May 1994 #2 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Turkey May 1994 #2 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Turkey Notes, circa 1994 (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Middle East II, April 1953; April 1954 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Middle East II, April 1953; April 1954-June 1954 (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Middle East II, November 1952; November 1953; June 1954; October 1958 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Middle East II, November 1952; November 1953; October 1958 (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Middle East II, November 1952; November 1953, October 1958 (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Middle East II, November 1953 (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Middle East II, November 1953 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 #1 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 #1 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 #1 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 #1 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 #1 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 #1 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 #1 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 (2-77); Central Europe 1997 (80-101), 1996; 1997 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 (2-77); Central Europe 1997 (80-101), 1996; 1997 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 (2-77); Central Europe 1997 (80-101), 1996; 1997 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 (2-77); Central Europe 1997 (80-101), 1996; 1997 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Eastern Europe October 1996 (2-77); Central Europe 1997 (80-101), 1996; 1997 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Notes on Eastern Europe, circa 1996 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #1 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #1 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #1 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #1 (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #1 (Box 18, Folder 18)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #1 (Box 18, Folder 19)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #1 (Box 18, Folder 20)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #2 (Box 18, Folder 21)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #2 (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #2 (Box 18, Folder 23)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #2 (Box 18, Folder 24)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #2 (Box 18, Folder 25)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #2 (Box 18, Folder 26)
- Central Europe-Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube 1997 #2 (Box 18, Folder 27)
- Notes on Berlin-Dresden-Prague-Danube, circa 1997 (Box 18, Folder 28)
- Europe I: Rhodes and Cyprus, July 1953; February 1954 (Box 18, Folder 29)
- Europe I: Cyprus and Athens, February 1954; August 1958 (Box 18, Folder 30)
- Europe I: Athens, Istanbul and Austria, September-October 1954; August 1958 (Box 18, Folder 31)
- Europe I: Italy, September 21, 1952; April 1953; September 1953 (Box 18, Folder 32)
- Europe I: Italy, September-October 1953 (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Europe I: Italy, September-October 1953; October 1954; October 1958 (Box 18, Folder 34)
- Europe I: Italy and Switzerland, October 1954 (Box 18, Folder 35)
- Europe I: Switzerland and Paris, October 1954 (Box 18, Folder 36)
- Europe I: Austria, September-October 1954 (Box 18, Folder 37)
- Europe I: Paris, October 1954 (Box 18, Folder 38)
- Europe I: France and Italy, September 21, 1952; September 1953, October 1953, October 1954; October 1958 (Box 18, Folder 39)
- Europe I: Italy, September 21 1952, April 1953-October 1953; April 1955; October 1958 (Box 18, Folder 40)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Notes on Russia, August 2003 (Box 19, Folder 15)
- St. Petersburg-Stockholm-Archipelago, July 2001 (Box 19, Folder 16)
- St. Petersburg-Stockholm-Archipelago, July 2001 (Box 19, Folder 17)
- St. Petersburg-Stockholm-Archipelago, July 2001 (Box 19, Folder 18)
- St. Petersburg-Stockholm-Archipelago, July 2001 (Box 19, Folder 19)
- St. Petersburg-Stockholm-Archipelago, July 2001 (Box 19, Folder 20)
- St. Petersburg-Stockholm-Archipelago, July 2001 (Box 19, Folder 21)
- St. Petersburg-Stockholm-Archipelago, July 2001 (Box 19, Folder 22)
- Notes on St. Petersburg-Stockholm-Archipelago, July 2001 (Box 19, Folder 23)